[Music]
hello everyone i missed you last week
because i was in bed with a back injury
that prevented me from filming
however i am well again and almost back
to normal but i'm taking things easy and
staying indoors for a few more days just
in case
[Music]
today i decided to make some chocolate
molds my portable stove top was being
finicky so i wasn't able to heat the
chocolate properly but i made it work
though my recipes didn't come out
perfect today i think the homemade feel
still gives them charm
i also baked a cake since i wanted to
experiment with potential flavors for my
wedding
today is raspberries and beets
[Music]
in this video i wanted to answer a
question that has been following me for
over a year since i started this channel
it was brought up in my last video i got
so many messages about it and it is why
do you live alone
in addition there are also those who are
curious why i don't live with my fiance
and the short answer is that i think how
normal my situation seems all depends on
your background
for example within my cultural
experience it is normal to live with
your family as an adult until you get
married
so this is all very relative on who you
are and where you come from and while i
do have my own little home i still spend
a lot of time with family
in terms of my relationship i simply
wanted to have my own place until we got
married
i told that to luke early on and he said
that it was my choice his love wasn't
conditional
[Music]
i like the feeling of living more
independently during this time before i
get married i've never had the chance to
live by myself i always had roommates or
shared a space in some way and i really
wanted to experience living somewhere
that felt like my own
i'd never had that my entire life
after a series of not great
relationships i knew that i would much
rather learn to enjoy life alone than be
with the wrong person
while i did eventually find someone i
was very ready to live a beautiful life
by myself
it had no less value and there were
benefits to both lifestyles
[Music]
do
while living separately from others
isn't necessary for me it was important
and taught me how i wanted to live and
what i was willing to compromise if i
let someone significant into my life
again
as someone who innately wants to please
people it can be easy for me to get
swept up and living the way someone else
wants me to live instead of
understanding how i want to live and
what i need
and through that journey of discovery i
found this gentle quiet rhythm
something i realized i wanted to bring
to all my future relationships
[Music]
so
while this time living alone is now
coming to an end it's been extremely
fruitful
and that's why i'm sharing this with you
because i think it's so important to
listen to your heart and not let other
forces pressure you into doing something
you don't want to do or are not ready
for
there will always be people that don't
understand and that's okay
what works for one relationship doesn't
work for another
[Music]
for me i've had my best experience by
letting go of what society says is
normal or right and instead just listen
to my heart
what feels right for me may not be for
you and that's the beauty and complexity
of human relationships each is different
and so interesting
[Music]
i missed you guys last week because i
hurt my back and it was quite painful
it was really really hard to do things
and this isn't
too unusual for me i used to work at
a department store in the basement and
it was
my job certain days to move a lot of
heavy boxes that were dropped off by the
post
and
one day i slipped and fell while holding
one of those boxes
and i seriously injured my back and i
was not able to go into work for a while
and since that that was like gosh like
four
four maybe even five years ago since
then
now and then just at least once a year
something happens where i tweak my back
again yes it's always a bit annoying but
i always get better in
a few days of taking a good amount of
rest
it's funny how your body kind of lets
you know eventually that they just need
to stop for a bit
and
take a break
relax
so i did that last week but i did keep
working on etsy orders and it has given
me so much joy to see such lovely
responses to my work
at the shop thank you so much it has
just been
so exciting to open again and to get so
much
lovely feedback and even just answer
your questions and communicate with you
and there's an option in each order to
leave a little note and so many of you
have left some
really lovely heartfelt notes really
enjoyed reading them and it's been very
very meaningful for me
so thank you thank you very much anyway
i usually just don't really talk about
my relationship or
the reason behind living a specific way
that's more private
but the
questions regarding why i live alone
have just continued kind of following me
on this channel which is completely
understandable i understand why someone
is curious about that
i have never lived alone and i've rarely
gotten that chance if anything i've had
my own room but i've still shared a
space with a lot of people and in many
ways i still do that i still visit my
family all the time you know absolutely
all the time i'm over there hanging out
with them but having a space that is my
own was a really positive experience for
me and something that i knew i needed to
experience especially before i get
married there are so many ways you know
i think to have healthy relationships
depending on what culture you come from
you know what is
normal is very very different
you know if anything living in a place
on my own
was very strange exceptionally strange
for me because in hispanic culture it is
expected you know to have multiple
generations under the same roof and
that's something i've always loved you
know my abuelita lived with us for many
years and she might live with us again
someday you know and
that is something that's always been a
very core part of my family life
so
i will most likely cultivate that again
you know of
having multiple generations under the
same roof when i'm older
and that is very normal for me and for
my mother's culture and that's something
that i've i have always seen as normal
even though people from another part of
the world might think that's really
strange
i know not everyone obviously has my
personality but something that's always
been hard for me is that when i care
about someone when i love someone
i want to
kind of
allow myself to be absorbed into their
world you know i want to turn into the
person that can make them most happy
and that is always a temptation to
cater
a hundred percent to other people as
opposed to really understanding also
what i need in order to be my best so
that i can
help other people as well that's so
important in order to keep that balance
you know and and that's something that
i've always struggled with relationships
in the past i would always get
completely absorbed whatever they liked
was what i liked whatever lifestyle they
wanted was now my lifestyle
anything that they approved of is what i
would be whatever they disproved of is
what i wouldn't be
and
it just felt like i would lose myself in
the process and i wouldn't know who i
was anymore
and that's a really
scary place to be that i'm sure many of
us experience it someplace or another
when you get lost in a situation or a
relationship or or maybe just generally
in life where you come to a point where
you're like who am i yeah so it was it
was been really fruitful to spend this
time on my own
so
yeah everyone's
journey is so individual and unique and
specific on their needs and
yeah so i just wanted to share that yeah
but yes i will not be living alone for
much longer i am terrified about that
idea it is such a big change
i also noticed some people
worried that i was very unhappy with the
decision i was making i wanted to
explain that i'm not unhappy i'm
actually very very excited for the
changes coming my way i'm very excited
to
live in a new home finally have a home
of my own
and all that is just so amazing and
wonderful to me
but it is a big change and that is
terrifying nonetheless yeah it's been
scary but that doesn't mean it's not
welcomed i i i will miss this home so
much
so so much but
i am ready to also have a home of my own
and to start a new journey in a new
life with my best friend
stay safe take care of yourself
i'm sending my love
and i will see you next week goodbye
[Music]